<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Zombie Apocolypse Survival Training (ZAST)]]></title>
  <link href="http://everzast.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://everzast.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-02-15T04:56:53-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://everzast.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Fussell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Aiki Jujitsu]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/aiki-jujitsu/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-01T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/aiki-jujitsu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>You need to be always armed if there are zombies floating around.  Zombies are rarely fast, but they can be
stealthy as they wander around&hellip; and some can hide in the ground&hellip; behind trees.  You need to be ready and
able to respond to a sudden threat appearing.</p>

<p>Ideally you are heavily armed and can dispose of the threat quickly, but if you are caught without a significant
weapon, you need to fight hand-to-hand.  As described elsewhere, a number of fighting arts from Japan have been
demilitarized postwar.  You do not want to learn to thumb-lock a zombie.  So although beautiful, something like
Aikido is not going to do you well.  Throwing zombie with Judo is also not something you want to do day-to-day
although I admit combining it with some bowling pins makes it sound pretty fun.</p>

<p>No, you want each interaction to end quickly and hopefully permanently.  I have not studied Zombie anatomy enough
to be sure, but I think Aiki Jujitsu may be one of the better anti-zombie martial arts sans weapons.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zombie Gear!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/zombie-gear/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-16T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/zombie-gear</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post contains other gear you might want and other sites that discuss preparation.  It started when I encountered
&lsquo;ZAPS&rsquo; while reading through the web.</p>

<ul>
<li> <a href="http://www.zapsgear.com">http://www.zapsgear.com</a></li>
</ul>


<p>In terms of other gear, you can divide it into a few different categories:</p>

<ul>
<li> Individual Survival and Effectiveness

<ul>
<li>Proper winter clothing, shoes, hats, gloves (winter and working), maybe swimming needs, etc.   This you can mostly get from REI, Sports Basement, and similar good camping and gear stores</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li> Group Survival

<ul>
<li>Tents, water conversions, vehicles capable of moving groups of people, packs able to transport water and other devices, water purifiers, etc.</li>
<li>Food acquisition tools: fishing, hunting, foraging, and hunting.</li>
<li>Note a lot of these would help the individual, but you should probably be thinking &ldquo;group&rdquo; when getting them.  A one-person tent is nice but not that helpful for groups.</li>
<li>Again, REI and similar stores are a good source</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li> Defense gear

<ul>
<li>This could be traps, fences, and the like.  Or defensive weaponry.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li> Offensive gear

<ul>
<li>This would be more serious weaponry that can &lsquo;assault&rsquo; zombies who control important positions or buildings</li>
<li>This isn&rsquo;t an area I am particularly concerned with</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Zombie Style!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/zombie-style/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-15T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/zombie-style</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Although there might be times that you are naked and have to operate properly in those circumstance, most of the
time you should have some kind of environmental protection.  Again, if you don&rsquo;t have a choice just grab something
that plausibly fits and is functional.  But if you have a choice, try to get good layers going.</p>

<h2>Layers</h2>

<p>I think of clothing as layers.  Working inward to outward.</p>

<ul>
<li> Layer-1: Sport = Tri-suit.  Casual = Underwear (and comfortable bra if needed).  Either also has socks.</li>
<li> Layer-2: Sport = Tennis (or jogging) shorts and biking shirt (See: <a href="http://supersonicfox.com/blog/what-does-the-fox-wear/">http://supersonicfox.com/blog/what-does-the-fox-wear/</a>).  Casual = Long pants and polo shirt (for a guy).  Either has a pair of sneakers if not trumped by the next layer.</li>
<li> Layer-3 (Inside the shell): This varies based on temperature

<ul>
<li>Nice: Nothing</li>
<li>Warm: Nothing</li>
<li>Hot: Nothing (drink lots of water if possible&hellip; stay out of sun&hellip; travel at night)</li>
<li>Cool: Shell from Layer-4</li>
<li>Cold: Fleece (either inside shell or alone)</li>
<li>Amazingly Cold: Start swapping out things in Layer-1 and 2 (e.g. silks for layer 1, wool for layer 2) and try again with Fleece</li>
<li>Antarctica: Space-suit like outer shell plus the stuff above</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li> Layer-4 (Outer shell): This varies a lot by the circumstances:

<ul>
<li>Melow: Nothing (1 &amp; 2 suffice)</li>
<li>Rainy: Nice Shell (I have a Patagonia)</li>
<li>Really Rainy: Nice Shell &amp; Swap to boots</li>
<li>Snowy: Better Shell if above wasn&rsquo;t good enough.  Better boots.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Other accessories / equipment go with the above.  As things get cold you need gloves, and ideally water/snow proof gloves.
A good set of skiing goggles will protect your eyes.  You may need a mask to protect your face.  Etc.</p>

<h2>Size</h2>

<p>Generally get things that fit you but have space (not too tight).  You may need to be carrying a bunch of other stuff <em>inside</em> your clothes.</p>

<h2>Colors</h2>

<p>Unless the Zombies like or dislike certain colors (Toro Zombies?)&hellip; please do not consider</p>

<h2>Styles</h2>

<p>Unless the Zombies like or dislike certain styles (Disco Zombies?)&hellip; please do not consider</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iaido]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/iaido/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-14T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/iaido</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Although Kendo is now &lsquo;dead&rsquo;, Iaido is still alive.  Iaido is a mostly solitary sword practice to prepare your skill with
a Katana (or Iaito / unsharpened Katana), your mental presence in a situation, and your ability to react <em>immediately</em>
(basically mindlessly) to a threat.</p>

<p>I went to an Iaido session, and although I disliked the pomp and circumstance, the practitioners and mage clearly
are trying to get good with a sword and are quite skilled and knowledgeable.</p>

<p>It meets every two weeks in my daughter&rsquo;s old ballet dance studio&hellip; interesting coincidence.  And it meets at a time
that I am usually playing tennis.  So I will simply drop a tennis session every other week, and start practicing Iaido
along with my daily ritual of tennis.  I will do the pomp for the session with the mage, but the rest of the time I will
be in my Fox uniform :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Be Careful What You Write About (2)?]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/be-careful-what-you-write-about-2/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-13T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/be-careful-what-you-write-about-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So my wife needed a new car to replace her persnickety Saab.  Long story short, I now also own a MB GL450.  Use it just
for work until the Apoc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Vehicle]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/vehicle/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-12T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/vehicle</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I previously covered &lsquo;driving&rsquo; (<a href="http://everzast.com/blog/drive-like-jason/">http://everzast.com/blog/drive-like-jason/</a>) after the Apoc, but what should you be driving like Jason?</p>

<h2>Learn Everything</h2>

<p>First, you need to make sure you can drive almost anything:</p>

<ul>
<li> Stick Shift?  Check!</li>
<li> Motorcycle? Check!</li>
<li> Bus? Check!</li>
<li> Bike? Check!</li>
<li> Plane?  &hellip;</li>
<li> Helicopter? &hellip;</li>
</ul>


<p>Fortunately the last two aren&rsquo;t &lsquo;driving&rsquo; but they are still a gap for me.  I <em>should</em> be able to fly a plane.  So
maybe eventually.</p>

<p>OK, now that you can drive everything.  You should be driving whatever is drivable.  There might be better things,
but if you have a fueled vehicle, you are in good shape.  Zombies are definitely slower than most vehicles out there.</p>

<h2>Better</h2>

<p>Now if you happen to have a few choices on vehicles, there are definitely better vehicles than other vehicles.
The critical things you are looking for are:</p>

<ul>
<li> Fuel Type</li>
<li> Speed!</li>
<li> Momentum!</li>
<li> Flexibility!</li>
<li> Range!</li>
</ul>


<p>Pretty much, the first factor is the category of the vehicle (Gas, Electric, etc.) and after you pick that, you need to
maximize the rest of the numbers.  Ideally you cover multiple fuel types and maximize all the rest.</p>

<p>Strangely the universe has set me up to have the perfect combination of vehicles.  Again, I need to be careful of what
I write about because it seems to come true.</p>

<p>My current vehicle garage looks like this:</p>

<ul>
<li> Scion TC:  Gas.  Good Mileage.  Fast-ish.  Stealth-ish.  About 250 mile range.  Front-wheel drive.</li>
<li> Range Rover HSE:  Gas.  Bad Mileage.  Can go through three feet of water.  About 300 mile range.  Four-wheel drive.</li>
<li> Tesla P85D:  Electric.  Awesome Mileage.  Awesome speed.  0-60 in &lt;4 seconds.  About 300 mile range.  Both gas and solar refuel.  All-wheel drive.</li>
<li> 2x Zero FX Motorcycle:  Electric.  Awesome mileage.  Awesome speed.  0-60 in some crazy number.  About 75 mile range.  Both gas and solar refuel.</li>
</ul>


<p>Several of the above I do not yet own, but that appears to be what my garage is meant to look like.  I am pretty sure that
has most Apoc scenarios covered&hellip;  Gas and Electric.  Fast on road or able to be off-road.  Four and two wheel variants.</p>

<p>I do love my Scion, but all the crazy-awesome vehicles beneath it make the Scion even better.  And make my family and
community safer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kendo]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/kendo/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-11T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/kendo</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My journey to learn the Katana continued last night.  I found a Kendo (Sword Way) class in Palo Alto, and talked with
the instructors as well as watching for a while.  I will not be taking this class because:</p>

<ul>
<li> It doesn&rsquo;t really teach Kendo</li>
<li> It doesn&rsquo;t teach effectively</li>
<li> It is at a horrible time for me</li>
</ul>


<p>What?  A Kendo class that doesn&rsquo;t teach The Way of the Sword?  How can that be?</p>

<p>Well, you need to understand a bit about the Japanese culture and history to understand why Kendo is not really Kendo.</p>

<p>The Japanese are an amazing people: they are incredibly disciplined with both body and mind.  This makes them very
powerful.  They do amazing things both individually and in groups.  The Japanese are also very <em>obedient</em>.  They
follow orders to the letter.  They obey their masters.</p>

<p>Where these traits came from, I do not know, but together they are <em>scary</em>.  If you read Artemis Fowl, read/watch Helsing,
or any number of other books and movies, you may have noticed that the most scary person in these are the guardians
of a &ldquo;master&rdquo;.  When you are guarding your master you have <em>exactly two</em> rules:</p>

<ul>
<li> I must protect my master</li>
<li> I must obey my master</li>
</ul>


<p>Two rules.  Only two.  &ldquo;I must be nice to pigeons!&rdquo;  Not a rule.  &ldquo;I must not run over babies with my Hummer!&rdquo;  Not a
rule.  When Asimov wrote the three laws of robotics, he added a third rule about self preservation, but that one is
actually redundant with the first rule as long as you are dealing with a single master.  Basically Asimov agrees with
my rules (or caused me to recognize my rules given I love Asimov&rsquo;s work).</p>

<p>In the small, scary guardians are fine.  Even Artemis tended not to abuse the world too much with his Butler.  But
when you have a highly disciplined <em>society</em> that obeys these two rules&hellip; bad things are going to happen.  Like WW2.</p>

<p>So Kendo was normal going into WW2: It was a way to learn how to wield a Katana.  I suspect the history of its development
went like this:</p>

<ul>
<li> To practice we will use our Katanas!  [Much mayhem]</li>
<li> To practice we will use an Iaito [Unsharpened Katana]!  [Much mayhem]</li>
<li> To practice we will use a Bokken [Wooden Unsharpened Sword]! [Still some mayhem]</li>
<li> To practice we will use a Shinai [Bamboo Sword]! Ah! That works and keeps people in one piece.</li>
</ul>


<p>So Kendo progressed to the Shinai as a weapon, but otherwise was exactly the same.  To wield a Katana you slice your
opponent, so to practice with a Shinai you make exactly the same motion.  That was Kendo with a Shinai.</p>

<p>Until WW2.</p>

<p>After WW2 Japan was rebuilt both physically and mentally.  I can&rsquo;t say how a group of people managed to do this to
themselves, but when they disarmed militarily, they similarly disarmed (boxed) themselves mentally too.  It is among
the more amazing cultural transformations I can imagine.  Almost like Divergent.</p>

<p>And within the box, you can no longer practice Kendo.  You can&rsquo;t practice wielding a Katana if you know you are supposed
to be disarmed.  That is dishonest to your principles.</p>

<p>But the Japanese also love traditions.  So they changed Kendo into being about &lsquo;tapping&rsquo;.  You could call it &lsquo;hitting&rsquo;,
but it really isn&rsquo;t.  And in either case, it <em>has nothing</em> to do with wielding a Katana.  It would actually mess you
up.</p>

<p>So very interesting.  Kendo isn&rsquo;t Kendo.</p>

<p>There was a period where pre-WW2 Kendo people were still around, and still did Kendo the right way.  They were called &lsquo;Heavy Hitters&rsquo;,
but that is a misnomer.  They were slicing you with a Shinai, not hitting you at all.  That is the way of the sword.
Still looking for one of them to teach me&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Locks!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/locks/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-10T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/locks</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote before about safety and how I don&rsquo;t want a safety on my guns.  That is because a safety is a delusion.  A
drawn weapon is not safe, so don&rsquo;t try to make it safer.  That is the dull-knife mentality.  I understand if you must
carry a loaded gun, a mechanical safety might be useful.  Better would be a grip lock that recognized your hand.  And I can come
up with better than that too because I am ridiculously creative nowadays.</p>

<p>But I don&rsquo;t have to carry a loaded gun, so I can simply &lsquo;lock it away&rsquo;.  Hence no safety.  Must undo locks and after
that, clearly I intend to use the nasty thing or I would relock it.</p>

<h2>Ultimate Lock</h2>

<p>The ultimate lock is the thing simply does not exist&hellip; or at least not to you.  My F-14 is very safely locked away.
As are all my ICBMs.  Nuclear subs.  Etc.</p>

<h2>Multiple Locks</h2>

<p>Even with the ultimate lock, it is useful to have multiple locks on things.  This isn&rsquo;t redundancy: you can&rsquo;t get in
with just one of the two locks&hellip; you must get <em>both</em> of them.</p>

<p>For example, my F-14 has multiple locks.  If you park it in front of my house, ready for me to jump in, it is unfortunately
still locked despite it&rsquo;s proximity.  It is actually ridiculously locked:</p>

<ul>
<li> It may have no fuel, and I can&rsquo;t tow an F-14 to a fighter-jet-fueling-station!</li>
<li> Even if I could, I don&rsquo;t know where a FJFS is!</li>
<li> Even if I could, I don&rsquo;t think they would let me fuel it (being a civilian and all)!</li>
<li> Even if I could, I don&rsquo;t think Moffet would let me pull it to their runway (civilian again) and Palo Alto might be too short!</li>
<li> EIIC: I don&rsquo;t have a helmet&hellip; but maybe you left that in there&hellip;</li>
<li> EIIC: I don&rsquo;t actually know how to fly an F-14.  So I better get a video game or mage to teach me.</li>
</ul>


<p>So my F-14 has at least seven locks on it.  Very unlikely I am going to accidentally get access to it.  Which suits me
fine: I don&rsquo;t think I will need my F-14 any time soon.  And if I do (Zombies and all), I think I can survive long enough
to undo the seven locks.</p>

<h2>Weapon locks</h2>

<p>Turns out all my weapons are locked pretty similarly to the F-14.  I simply don&rsquo;t own any of them.  So undoing the locks
will take quite a bit of forethought and a significant passage of time.  Much better and safer than a stupid safety :-)</p>

<p>I do carry seven tennis rackets though&hellip;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Be Careful What You Write About?]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/be-careful-what-you-write-about/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-09T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/be-careful-what-you-write-about</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Apparently I have the ability to cause me (and proximate Koi) to experience the things I am writing about&hellip;</p>

<p>I was working on checking out Christmas light strands, and it rained in California recently (See <a href="http://SupersonicFox.com/">http://SupersonicFox.com/</a>
for how shocking this is), and somehow there was a short.  Now in most houses this would trip something and you would
just flip a switch, but I live in the <a href="http://SlumsOfPaloAlto.com/">http://SlumsOfPaloAlto.com/</a> in a rented house, so my house is not normal.
And it <em>blew out</em> the circuit breaker vs. doing something easily recoverable.</p>

<p>A call to an electrician on a Sunday provided no results, and the circuit that was blown holds several thousand dollars
of meat for <a href="http://FullOfLifeFood.com">http://FullOfLifeFood.com</a>.</p>

<p>So I needed to either run a long extension cord, or get me some electricity.</p>

<p>One of my rules is that I don&rsquo;t buy <em>bad stuff</em>.  I don&rsquo;t work with <em>bad people</em> either (preferring friendly mages or at
least friendly competent people).  I also never <em>cross-buy</em>: Use one person&rsquo;s resources to buy from a different person.
 So I don&rsquo;t use amazon to buy from a store or a store to buy from amazon.  I buy lots of things from Amazon, but however
 fast they deliver&hellip; without the Quad-Copter-Droid system I was not going to get something good from Amazon in the time required
 to save the meat.</p>

<p>So I went to <a href="http://HomeDepot.com">http://HomeDepot.com</a> and studied the reviews.  I saw a lot of generators, but they all weighed 100+ pounds.
Yes, I can lift 100+ pounds, but try to avoid it.  And I buy things intending that my wife and daughters can use them
if they need to.  Pretty sure Katrina can&rsquo;t lift 100 pounds.</p>

<p>But in amongst these behemoths was a diamond: a Ryobi generator that weighs maybe 40 pounds.  I have Ryobi equipment and
they are very nice.  Best battery system I have.  So a trip to two Home Depots (stores are bad at tracking inventory)
and surviving the nastiest parking lot traffic I have been in recently, and I now have the Ryobi generator.  The
reviews said to use different oil and a different plug, so I bought the oil but didn&rsquo;t know the size of the plug without
opening the box.</p>

<p>Strangely the box and instructions never mentioned the gas size, but a small spill and a non-spill confirm it is a bit
less than a gallon (or my two-gallon gas can is quite a bit more than two gallons).</p>

<p>Very nice generator.  Supposedly quiet.  If that is true, I hope never to need one of the behemoths!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Body in Motion]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/a-body-in-motion/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-08T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/a-body-in-motion</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>is more likely to live.</p>

<p>Especially when you are on your own or in small groups, you need to be <em>in motion</em>.  If you are completely still,
you are an easy target or prey.  A zombie could just quietly walk up to you and take a bite.  Doesn&rsquo;t feel good, and
in some Apocs, you are now suddenly on the other side and all this training has gone to waste.</p>

<p>Biting things that are moving around is much harder.</p>

<p>Yes, you could just dance around the room and you have started the first level of being in motion.  But to get to the
real &lsquo;in motion&rsquo;, you should also be trying to achieve something.  Something very valuable.  Because a lot has to get
done after the Apoc, and there are a lot fewer people around&hellip; so if you have a mirror, you might want to look into it
and start there.</p>

<p>The Postman, Mad Max, Divergent, Hunger Games, etc. all teach us that <em>moving around purposefully</em> is far more effective than
either not moving or not having a purpose.  So try it out today so you are ready for tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Raising Resilient!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/raising-resilient/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-07T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/raising-resilient</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>People try to raise all kinds of kids.  Clearly many of these parents have strange motives, and the kids come out quite twisted
by these motives.  Personally, I view myself as the smartest person on the planet (by choosing and being chosen
by Rebecca), so I don&rsquo;t have to make my kids prove to me how much smarter than me they are.  They do anyway&hellip;. It makes me
happy mostly&hellip; a little sad at my failings&hellip;</p>

<p>So my kids are smarter than me without being stressed by it?  YES!</p>

<p>So my kids are SEL-er than me without being stressed by it?  YES!</p>

<p>So I can crush them at the gun range without them being stressed by it?  YES!</p>

<p>And at the miniature golf course, they are working themselves up to my level?  YES!</p>

<p>Kids are meant to <em>have fun</em>.  If they aren&rsquo;t <em>having fun</em> then the fault is all on their parents.  On YOU!</p>

<p>Yes, kids have to do chores, go to school, do homework, hang with friends, go to sleep, &hellip; and it is your responsibility
to make all these things be fun.  Or at least &ldquo;easily doable&rdquo;.  Because after the Apoc, kids are going to have to easily
do a lot of nastier things&hellip; so they better be resilient.  And good runners.  Or good tree climbers.  Ideally both!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Katana!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/katana/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-06T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/katana</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am trying to learn to wield a Katana: a Japanese sword.  Turns out that buying a Katana is not
very difficult, but learning how to wield a Katana is ridiculously difficult.  I live in an area that
has many insane (aka &lsquo;awesome&rsquo;) people, but I may have to drive significant amount of hours to find Katana Mages.</p>

<p>The drive is worth it, so I don&rsquo;t have a problem with this equation.  Just surprising&hellip;.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Safety!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/safety/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-05T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/safety</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Continuing further into the jungle&hellip; no safetys!  If I draw a gun, I am about to <em>kill you</em>.  Make your choice, you are opposed
by lethal force.  I drew a gun.  Lethal (life ending in a split of a second) force.   If you wish to live, please move
along.  I <em>do not</em> want to kill you.  But if you do not move along, I will.  Simple choice.   If you look at my shot pattern,
you will recognize that this is not a variable.  I spray within a centimeter.   Yes.  Seriously.   I am a professional
shooter.  I was taught by myself and a professional mage name Rick.  I &ldquo;don&rsquo;t miss&rdquo;.   Kill me or move along.  The third option neither you or I will enjoy.</p>

<h2>It is all about the revolvers!</h2>

<p>So the dynamics of revolvers are very much more interesting than automatics.  If you have a great automatic, you
have a great &lsquo;touch&rsquo; weapon.  Touch it.  People die.  Or targets get nasty holes.  A revolver has two epic choices.
Flow through the trigger, or &lsquo;touch&rsquo; it.  If you do not cock (with your other hand, fool!) the revolver, the flow is
incredibly satisfying.  If you precock the instrument-of-destruction, then things are simpler.  The first feels like
aikido, the second like the god of death.  Interesting alternatives.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Weapon Up!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/weapon-up/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-04T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/weapon-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>OK, so now we get into the heart of the jungle: after the Apoc, you need to be armed.  Armed with what?  Three things:</p>

<ul>
<li> An ability to defend yourself and your community without a weapon</li>
<li> An ability to defend yourself and your community with a melee weapon</li>
<li> An ability to defend yourself and your community with a ranged weapon</li>
</ul>


<p>And ideally for the weapons, you have a fricken-awesome weapon that can last until the Apoc ends&hellip; which could be
never&hellip; so pick wisely.  And get a sensei or mage to teach you.  And practice.  1000 hours.</p>

<h2>Weapon Cheats</h2>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t want to learn how to use a weapon, you can cheat but it will take possibly more time and be less fricken-awesome.</p>

<p>For example, I swing a tennis racket like a two-headed axe.  I don&rsquo;t actually own a two-headed axe, but I am pretty sure if
it weighs about the same as my tennis racket, I can swing it.  At 100+ MPH.  Likely effective defense.</p>

<p>You could do the same thing with darts.  Maybe Javelin.  Shot-put.  Maybe bowling although if zombies can jump that won&rsquo;t
be very effective.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Me Some Electricity!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/get-me-some-electricity/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-03T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/get-me-some-electricity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I already wrote how you should shun electricity (<a href="http://everzast.com/blog/shun-electricity/">http://everzast.com/blog/shun-electricity/</a>).  That is true unless you
have your own redundant source of electricity.
The main wires are going to all be down, so you are going to need to get another source.  You could stockpile a lot
of gas or diesel fuel.  But you need to be mobile, so storing and transporting it is going to be a problem.  I recommend
you watch Mad Max <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mad_Max">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mad_Max</a> to get some ideas about that.  Even if &ldquo;the natives&rdquo; are not
quite so unfriendly, the solution is about the same.  Not sure how many oil rigs will be working, so you might want
to buy and fill the truck now.  You could probably park it in an RV parking lot.  Or on the street, but some people
have issues with that, and some cities laws against it.  I believe those laws are unconstitutional, so you might want to
park now to get the wheels of justice in motion.</p>

<p>A slightly smaller version of the same idea is a Class-A motorhome.  You can find out more about them at <a href="http://butterflybus.org">http://butterflybus.org</a>.
The fuel tank of a Diesel-Pusher can be up to 150 gallons, so you have a pretty good reservoir there.  I wouldn&rsquo;t recommend moving it very
much or you will lose a lot of those gallons (about one per eight miles traveled).  And parking has a similar problem.</p>

<p>An alternative to liquid fuels is solar fuel.  In only a few of the dystopias is the sun blotted from the sky.
In that case, you should have a backup plan, so maybe you need the liquid fuels and a solar solution.  But if you had
to pick, getting a few-thousand-dollar solar solution seems the logical first step.</p>

<p>Amazingly these are already reasonable priced for mobile versions.  So buy two, and start reading up on motorhomes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drive Like Jason!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/drive-like-jason/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-02T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/drive-like-jason</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The future will have roads and automobiles.  Blowing up all the roads in the United States would imply that the Earth
is no longer around.  ZAST will not help you if the earth is no longer here.  Some other mage may be able to help you
with that.  Probably a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technomage">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technomage</a>, but I have no idea how to find one.</p>

<p>OK, so we have roads and automobiles, we just need gas to make the cars move and drivers to drive them around.
And we don&rsquo;t need just any kind of driver.  Old women from Pasadena won&rsquo;t make the cut.  We need Jason Statham.
We need transporters (<a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0293662/">http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0293662/</a>).</p>

<h2>How to be a transporter</h2>

<p>To be a transporter, you need particular skills and a particular attitude.  The skills you need are demonstrated
by Jason, but I suspect taking a driving course is a better way to learn.  Something like <a href="http://SkipBarber.com">http://SkipBarber.com</a>.
Even better would be a transporter-like simulation and training that included Jason in the car with you.  Not
sure where to get that.</p>

<p>For getting the right attitude you don&rsquo;t need Jason in the car with you.  Watching the transporter will help.
Thinking you are &lsquo;transporting&rsquo; something will also help.  You will notice in the movie that transporters
do not drive particularly quickly.  They drive at normal speed.  The <em>can</em> drive ridiculously quickly, but
they don&rsquo;t.  Normal conditions (pre Apoc, no people trying to kill you), normal behavior.  And by normal,
I mean:</p>

<ul>
<li> At flow speed, or slightly faster (but don&rsquo;t annoy the highway patrol)</li>
<li> Very defensively.  Not slowly (addressed that above) but consider that all cars are trying to kill you.

<ul>
<li>Yes, I know.  This is pre Apoc.  But even pre-Apoc or without any &lsquo;thugs&rsquo; many people <em>can</em> kill you with their cars.  I am pretty sure dieing of manslaughter doesn&rsquo;t feel any different from being murdered</li>
<li>OK, now that all the cars are trying to kill you, what do you do?  Avoid being anywhere near cars!

<ul>
<li>Take roads that have less cars on them.</li>
<li>If you are on a bike, stay on the trails.</li>
<li>If you are with other cars, just keep them at a distance.  Never have a car to your side for longer than needed to pass them.  Obey the three-second rule as much as possible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Yes, this may seem totally not-cool.  I never said you would <em>look cool</em>.  I said you would survive the Apoc.
Which is actually <em>cooler</em>?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All About the Bass]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/all-about-the-bass/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-01T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/all-about-the-bass</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is specifically for the human male.  If you are either not-human or not-male, please move along&hellip;. <a href="http://everzast.com/blog/drive-like-jason/">http://everzast.com/blog/drive-like-jason/</a></p>

<p>OK, now that they are gone, I am going to fix you.  Somehow society has broken some of you to thinking that
some women are more physically attractive than other women.  This is a lie.  And if your brain is thinking this, it is
because you have been brain-washed and aren&rsquo;t your right self.</p>

<p>First, go watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7PCkvCPvDXk&amp;noredirect=1">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7PCkvCPvDXk&amp;noredirect=1</a> and truly listen and watch that movie.</p>

<p>OK, now excepting the guy wandering through the video every once in a while, you can tell if you are &lsquo;broken&rsquo; if
you don&rsquo;t want to please every last one of those women.</p>

<p>OK, so how to fix you?  You can watch this movie over and over.  You can watch a lot of videos.  Watch the women in your neighborhood.
And keep asking why wouldn&rsquo;t I want to please her?</p>

<h3>Monogamy</h3>

<p>Oh, and to make it perfectly clear, you must also be completely monogamous while doing this activity.  If you aren&rsquo;t
monogamous, please fix that.  I am pretty sure your wife, love, companion, girlfriend is monogamous, so what is your
problem?  Oh?  Well then find a local news stand, buy a magazine, and learn how to get relief the good old fashioned
way.  Or there is this thing called the internet.  It can help.  But being monogamous is simply a choice.  A very simple
one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Be a Mage]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/how-to-be-a-mage/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-30T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/how-to-be-a-mage</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a ZAS mage.  A mage is someone that is so skilled with something that it looks like magic.  And it usually requires
about ten thousand hours to become a mage.  I became a software mage by reading and writing software for 40 years, 25 years of which
were full time, and 8 years of which were at startups.  This works out to be:</p>

<ul>
<li> 15 years at maybe 500 hours a year, or 7,500 hours</li>
<li> 17 years at maybe 2000 hours a year, or 34,000 hours</li>
<li> 8 years at maybe 4000 hours a year, or 32,000 hours</li>
</ul>


<p>So I definitely passed the 10,000 hour mark by quite a bit.  I was mostly self-taught but leveraged about 2000 great books and Smalltalk-80 to
get me to where I am today.</p>

<p>I am also a tennis mage (<a href="http://supersonicfox.com/blog/being-a-mage/">http://supersonicfox.com/blog/being-a-mage/</a>) and I leveraged a great mage plus youth playing to make it take me more like 1000 hours.  That is
unusually fast to become a mage.</p>

<p>But I became a ZAS mage even faster.  I don&rsquo;t actually recommend this path to anyone, but through it I became a mage almost instantly.
It was by surviving several simultaneous perils to my family.  And by working through these perils (all at once), I changed: I leveled-up.</p>

<p>So if you want the quick path, it is probably something similar to the peril route.  But if you are patient and can put in ten thousand
hours, that is probably the better way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get in Shape!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/get-in-shape/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-29T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/get-in-shape</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, zombies are slow.  But maybe not.  And velociraptors aren&rsquo;t slow.  And some things are wicked fast but can&rsquo;t climb.</p>

<p>It takes a good bit of time to get in good shape, and without electricity or running water, I am pretty sure the YMCA
will not be a great place to hang out.  So get in shape now.  Learn to run a couple miles.  Most animals and zombies give
up during the second mile.  Learn to do a pull up.  Then twenty.  Good, now you can climb a tree.</p>

<p>And try to get rid of some of that excess fat.  Yes, I know, fat tastes good, but I don&rsquo;t think you want to literally be
a tasty morsel.</p>

<p>Oh, and pass the word along to anyone you love.  We are trying to keep our community, so the maxim &ldquo;Run faster than someone else&rdquo;
is not what you are looking for.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shun Electricity!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/shun-electricity/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-28T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/shun-electricity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love electricity as much as the next person who stuck two pieces of metal into the wall sockets and arced between them, blowing out the circuit,
and frying the pennies (in my case).  I have an electric phone, rode an electric motorcycle, lust for an electric car, and
am writing this on an electric computer.</p>

<p>Pretty sure no electricity after the Apoc.</p>

<p>Again, sorry about that.</p>

<p>So, if you have a beautiful Tesla, you better figure out how you are going to drag that sucker around town.  Or find a really
nice generator that somehow can recharge that sucker, put generator into the trunk or frunk of the Tesla, and then you
are really mobile.</p>

<p>Electric guitar&hellip; switch to acoustic.</p>

<p>Electric shaver&hellip; grow a beard (fool).</p>

<p>Candles&hellip; gas stove&hellip; pens&hellip; bards&hellip;</p>

<p>I would also say &lsquo;Shun really heavy things&rsquo; like pianos.  My daughters can play the piano, but they also can play the flute
and violin.  Much more portable.  Pianos are good sources of: &lsquo;wood&rsquo;, &lsquo;wires&rsquo;, &lsquo;plastic&rsquo;, &lsquo;planks&rsquo;, &lsquo;metal&rsquo;, &lsquo;coffins&rsquo;, [come on, I know you can do it]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
