<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Zombie Apocolypse Survival Training (ZAST or EverZast)]]></title>
  <link href="http://everzast.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://everzast.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-26T09:00:01-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://everzast.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Fussell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get In Shape!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/get-in-shape/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-29T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/get-in-shape</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, zombies are slow.  But maybe not.  And velociraptors aren&rsquo;t slow.  And some things are wicked fast but can&rsquo;t climb.</p>

<p>It takes a good bit of time to get in good shape, and without electricity or running water, I am pretty sure the YMCA
will not be a great place to hang out.  So get in shape now.  Learn to run a couple miles.  Most animals and zombies give
up during the second mile.  Learn to do a pull up.  Then twenty.  Good, now you can climb a tree.</p>

<p>And try to get rid of some of that excess fat.  Yes, I know, fat tastes good, but I don&rsquo;t think you want to literally be
a tasty morsel.</p>

<p>Oh, and pass the word along to anyone you love.  We are trying to keep our community, so the maxim &ldquo;Run faster than someone else&rdquo;
is not what you are looking for.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shun Electricity!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/shun-electricity/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-28T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/shun-electricity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love electricity as much as the next person who stuck two pieces of metal into the wall sockets and arced between them, blowing out the circuit,
and frying the pennies (in my case).  I have an electric phone, rode an electric motorcycle, lust for an electric car, and
am writing this on an electric computer.</p>

<p>Pretty sure no electricity after the Apoc.</p>

<p>Again, sorry about that.</p>

<p>So, if you have a beautiful Tesla, you better figure out how you are going to drag that sucker around town.  Or find a really
nice generator that somehow can recharge that sucker, put generator into the trunk or frunk of the Tesla, and then you
are really mobile.</p>

<p>Electric guitar&hellip; switch to acoustic.</p>

<p>Electric shaver&hellip; grow a beard (fool).</p>

<p>Candles&hellip; gas stove&hellip; pens&hellip; bards&hellip;</p>

<p>I would also say &lsquo;Shun really heavy things&rsquo; like pianos.  My daughters can play the piano, but they also can play the flute
and violin.  Much more portable.  Pianos are good sources of: &lsquo;wood&rsquo;, &lsquo;wires&rsquo;, &lsquo;plastic&rsquo;, &lsquo;planks&rsquo;, &lsquo;metal&rsquo;, &lsquo;coffins&rsquo;, [come on, I know you can do it]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creativity!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/creativity/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-27T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/creativity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Next, you have to be creative.  But no cannibalism.</p>

<p>If you see a hammer think: hammer, piece of wood, piece of metal, tiny crutch for a schnauzer, poorly weighted and very
dull throwing axe, [keep going, I know you have it in you]</p>

<p>If you see a neighbor&rsquo;s schnauzer think: food, paper fetcher (useless), pooper (maybe), supplier of poop for a catapult (getting somewhere), [&hellip;]</p>

<p>Yes, being creative and being insane are not particularly distinguishable.  Sorry about that.  Try it out, or move along (Zombie fodder).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redundancy!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/redundancy/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-26T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/redundancy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Strangely the second most important skill after &ldquo;Freeing Your Mind&rdquo; will be redundancy.</p>

<p>Redundancy is the art of having a &ldquo;live&rdquo; equivalent or &ldquo;hot&rdquo; spare to basically everything.
If you have this, and one item fails (Zombie Alert Warning System: ZAWS), then the backup item (ZAW2) is <em>incredibly</em>
unlikely to fail at exactly the same time.   If ZAWS1 and ZAWS2 fail at <em>exactly</em> the same time, then you did not
have a real ZAWS at all, and we will deal with avoiding that problem later (you do know what QA is right?).</p>

<p>Redundancy is incredibly valuable in all things.  Except in marriage.  Monogamy is clearly superior.  But even then you
should have a Hot Spare readily available.  Because you never know do you?  Zombies and all!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Your Mind!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/free-your-mind/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-25T20:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/free-your-mind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The number one skill you must have after the Apoc is to &ldquo;Free Your Mind&rdquo;.  You can not have any negative assumptions about
almost anything.  Again, please trust me.  Amazon Asian Woman!  Might be useful.  Effervescent Ebony Girls!  Might be useful.
Both are amazingly hot, and likely the sources for Apoc Gen2.  If you can&rsquo;t see that, please get your glasses, your cojones,
or whatever does the looking for your body, cleaned and lubed.  Today I hugged #1 and #2 and the ethnicity of neither
affected the hardness of my whatever.</p>

<p>Do the sames girls, but it is hard for me to understand what your hotness sees in a balding wizard like me.  Guest lectures
are quite welcome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site Launch!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/site-launch/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-25T18:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/site-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been working on building up various skills, but wasn&rsquo;t really quite sure &lsquo;why?&rsquo;.  They started forming a pattern
though, and just a few days ago I came up with the title: &ldquo;Zombie Apocalypse Training (or ZAT)&rdquo; and formally used
that when I invited someone to join me for handgun training.</p>

<p>I changed that to &lsquo;ZAP&rsquo; (Preparation) because that is more fun, but ultimately I had to get a URL.  Somehow I realized
&lsquo;training&rsquo; by itself didn&rsquo;t make much sense: I am training to cause the Apoc?  No, I want my community to survive after
the Apoc, so now I was up to &lsquo;ZAST&rsquo;.  That URL was for sale, but I didn&rsquo;t know the price and it was likely a few hundred dollars.</p>

<p>One more shift and voila: EverZast&hellip; ZAST to last forever after the Apoc.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
