<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Zombie Apocolypse Survival Training (ZAST or EverZast)]]></title>
  <link href="http://everzast.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://everzast.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-27T18:30:18-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://everzast.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Fussell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get Me Some Electricity!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/get-me-some-electricity/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-03T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/get-me-some-electricity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I already wrote how you should shun electricity.  That is true unless you have your own redundant source of electricity.
The main wires are going to all be down, so you are going to need to get another source.  You could stockpile a lot
of gas or diesel fuel.  But you need to be mobile, so storing and transporting it is going to be a problem.  I recommend
you watch Mad Max <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mad_Max">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mad_Max</a> to get some ideas about that.  Even if &ldquo;the natives&rdquo; are not
quite so unfriendly, the solution is about the same.  Not sure how many fuel pumps will be working, so you might want
to buy and fill the truck now.  You could probably park it in an RV parking lot.  Or on the street, but some people
have issues with that, and some cities laws against it.</p>

<p>A slightly smaller version of the same idea is a Class-A motorhome.  You can find out more about them at <a href="http://butterflybus.org">http://butterflybus.org</a>.
The fuel tank of a DP can be up to 150 gallons, so you have a pretty good reservoir there.  I wouldn&rsquo;t recommend moving it very
much or you will lose a lot of those gallons (about one per eight miles traveled).  And parking has a similar problem.</p>

<p>An alternative to liquid fuels is simply solar fuel.  In only a few of the dystopias is the sun blotted from the sky.
In that case, you should have a backup plan, so maybe you need the liquid fuels and a solar solution.  But if you had
to pick, getting a few-thousand-dollar solar solution seems the logical first step.</p>

<p>Amazingly these are already reasonable priced for mobile versions.  So buy two, and start reading up on motorhomes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Drive Like Jason!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/drive-like-jason/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-02T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/drive-like-jason</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The future will have roads and automobiles.  Blowing up all the roads in the United States would imply that the Earth
is no longer around.  ZAST will not help you if the earth is no longer here.  Some other mage may be able to help you
with that.  Probably a <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technomage">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Technomage</a>, but I have no idea how to find one.</p>

<p>OK, so we have roads and automobiles, we just need gas to make the cars move and drivers to drive them around.
And we don&rsquo;t need just any kind of driver.  Old women from Pasadena won&rsquo;t make the cut.  We need Jason Statham.
We need transporters (<a href="http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0293662/">http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0293662/</a>).</p>

<h2>How to be a transporter</h2>

<p>To be a transporter, you need particular skills and a particular attitude.  The skills you need are demonstrated
by Jason, but I suspect taking a driving course is a better way to learn.  Something like <a href="http://SkipBarber.com">http://SkipBarber.com</a>.
Even better would be a transporter-like simulation and training that included Jason in the car with you.  Not
sure where to get that.</p>

<p>For getting the right attitude you don&rsquo;t need Jason in the car with you.  Watching the transporter will help.
Thinking you are &lsquo;transporting&rsquo; something will also help.  You will notice in the movie that transporters
do not drive particularly quickly.  They drive at normal speed.  The <em>can</em> drive ridiculously quickly, but
they don&rsquo;t.  Normal conditions (pre Apoc, no people trying to kill you), normal behavior.  And by normal,
I mean:</p>

<ul>
<li> At flow speed, or slightly faster (but don&rsquo;t annoy the highway patrol)</li>
<li> Very defensively.  Not slowly (addressed that above) but consider that all cars are trying to kill you.

<ul>
<li>Yes, I know.  This is pre Apoc.  But even pre-Apoc or without any &lsquo;thugs&rsquo; many people <em>can</em> kill you with their cars.  I am pretty sure dieing of manslaughter doesn&rsquo;t feel any different from being murdered</li>
<li>OK, now that all the cars are trying to kill you, what do you do?  Avoid being anywhere near cars!

<ul>
<li>Take roads that have less cars on them.</li>
<li>If you are on a bike, stay on the trails.</li>
<li>If you are with other cars, just keep them at a distance.  Never have a car to your side for longer than needed to pass them.  Obey the three-second rule as much as possible.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Yes, this may seem totally not-cool.  I never said you would <em>look cool</em>.  I said you would survive the Apoc.
Which is actually <em>cooler</em>?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[All About the Bass]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/all-about-the-bass/"/>
    <updated>2014-12-01T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/all-about-the-bass</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post is specifically for the human male.  If you are either not-human or not-male, please move along&hellip;. <a href="http://everzast.com/blog/drive-like-jason/">http://everzast.com/blog/drive-like-jason/</a></p>

<p>OK, now that they are gone, I am going to fix you.  Somehow society has broken some of you to thinking that
some women are more physically attractive than other women.  This is a lie.  And if your brain is thinking this, it is
because you have been brain-washed and aren&rsquo;t your right self.</p>

<p>First, go watch <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7PCkvCPvDXk&amp;noredirect=1">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7PCkvCPvDXk&amp;noredirect=1</a> and truly listen and watch that movie.</p>

<p>OK, now excepting the guy wandering through the video every once in a while, you can tell if you are &lsquo;broken&rsquo; if
you don&rsquo;t want to please every last one of those women.</p>

<p>OK, so how to fix you?  You can watch this movie over and over.  You can watch a lot of videos.  Watch the women in your neighborhood.
And keep asking why wouldn&rsquo;t I want to please her?</p>

<h3>Monogamy</h3>

<p>Oh, and to make it perfectly clear, you must also be completely monogamous while doing this activity.  If you aren&rsquo;t
monogamous, please fix that.  I am pretty sure your wife, love, companion, girlfriend is monogamous, so what is your
problem?  Oh?  Well then find a local news stand, buy a magazine, and learn how to get relief the good old fashioned
way.  Or there is this thing called the internet.  It can help.  But being monogamous is simply a choice.  A very simple
one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Five Perils]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/five-perils/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-30T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/five-perils</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am a ZAS mage.  A mage is someone that is so skilled with something that it looks like magic.  And it usually requires
about ten thousand hours to become a mage.  I became a software mage by reading and writing software for 40 years, 25 years of which
were full time, and 8 years of which were at startups.  This works out to be:</p>

<ul>
<li> 15 years at maybe 500 hours a year, or 7,500 hours</li>
<li> 17 years at maybe 2000 hours a year, or 34,000 hours</li>
<li> 8 years at maybe 4000 hours a year, or 32,000 hours</li>
</ul>


<p>So I definitely passed the 10,000 hour mark by quite a bit.  I was mostly self-taught but leveraged about 2000 great books and Smalltalk-80 to
get me to where I am today.</p>

<p>I am also a tennis mage (<a href="http://supersonicfox.com/blog/being-a-mage/">http://supersonicfox.com/blog/being-a-mage/</a>) and I leveraged a great mage plus youth playing to make it take me more like 1000 hours.  That is
unusually fast to become a mage.</p>

<p>But I became a ZAS mage even faster.  I don&rsquo;t actually recommend this path to anyone, but through it I became a mage almost instantly.
It was by surviving five perils.</p>

<p>The first four were all pretty major:</p>

<ul>
<li> I was going bankrupt</li>
<li> I got fired</li>
<li> My family got evicted without notice (owner reoccupation)</li>
<li> I gave away almost all my possessions (in case we had to move to a smaller place)</li>
</ul>


<p>after all these things happened, and we had recovered from them (new job, money in bank, new home, acceptance of having no possessions)
my family was hit with a fifth peril worse than all of the above&hellip; combined&hellip;   And I changed: I leveled-up.</p>

<p>So if you want the quick path, it is probably something like the above.  But if you are patient and can put in ten thousand
hours, that is probably the better way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Get in Shape!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/get-in-shape/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-29T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/get-in-shape</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yes, zombies are slow.  But maybe not.  And velociraptors aren&rsquo;t slow.  And some things are wicked fast but can&rsquo;t climb.</p>

<p>It takes a good bit of time to get in good shape, and without electricity or running water, I am pretty sure the YMCA
will not be a great place to hang out.  So get in shape now.  Learn to run a couple miles.  Most animals and zombies give
up during the second mile.  Learn to do a pull up.  Then twenty.  Good, now you can climb a tree.</p>

<p>And try to get rid of some of that excess fat.  Yes, I know, fat tastes good, but I don&rsquo;t think you want to literally be
a tasty morsel.</p>

<p>Oh, and pass the word along to anyone you love.  We are trying to keep our community, so the maxim &ldquo;Run faster than someone else&rdquo;
is not what you are looking for.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shun Electricity!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/shun-electricity/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-28T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/shun-electricity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love electricity as much as the next person who stuck two pieces of metal into the wall sockets and arced between them, blowing out the circuit,
and frying the pennies (in my case).  I have an electric phone, rode an electric motorcycle, lust for an electric car, and
am writing this on an electric computer.</p>

<p>Pretty sure no electricity after the Apoc.</p>

<p>Again, sorry about that.</p>

<p>So, if you have a beautiful Tesla, you better figure out how you are going to drag that sucker around town.  Or find a really
nice generator that somehow can recharge that sucker, put generator into the trunk or frunk of the Tesla, and then you
are really mobile.</p>

<p>Electric guitar&hellip; switch to acoustic.</p>

<p>Electric shaver&hellip; grow a beard (fool).</p>

<p>Candles&hellip; gas stove&hellip; pens&hellip; bards&hellip;</p>

<p>I would also say &lsquo;Shun really heavy things&rsquo; like pianos.  My daughters can play the piano, but they also can play the flute
and violin.  Much more portable.  Pianos are good sources of: &lsquo;wood&rsquo;, &lsquo;wires&rsquo;, &lsquo;plastic&rsquo;, &lsquo;planks&rsquo;, &lsquo;metal&rsquo;, &lsquo;coffins&rsquo;, [come on, I know you can do it]</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Creativity!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/creativity/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-27T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/creativity</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Next, you have to be creative.  But no cannibalism.</p>

<p>If you see a hammer think: hammer, piece of wood, piece of metal, tiny crutch for a schnauzer, poorly weighted and very
dull throwing axe, [keep going, I know you have it in you]</p>

<p>If you see a neighbor&rsquo;s schnauzer think: food, paper fetcher (useless), pooper (maybe), supplier of poop for a catapult (getting somewhere), [&hellip;]</p>

<p>Yes, being creative and being insane are not particularly distinguishable.  Sorry about that.  Try it out, or move along (Zombie fodder).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Redundancy!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/redundancy/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-26T06:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/redundancy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Strangely the second most important skill after &ldquo;Freeing Your Mind&rdquo; will be redundancy.</p>

<p>Redundancy is the art of having a &ldquo;live&rdquo; equivalent or &ldquo;hot&rdquo; spare to basically everything.
If you have this, and one item fails (Zombie Alert Warning System: ZAWS), then the backup item (ZAW2) is <em>incredibly</em>
unlikely to fail at exactly the same time.   If ZAWS1 and ZAWS2 fail at <em>exactly</em> the same time, then you did not
have a real ZAWS at all, and we will deal with avoiding that problem later (you do know what QA is right?).</p>

<p>Redundancy is incredibly valuable in all things.  Except in marriage.  Monogamy is clearly superior.  But even then you
should have a Hot Spare readily available.  Because you never know do you?  Zombies and all!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Your Mind!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/free-your-mind/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-25T20:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/free-your-mind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The number one skill you must have after the Apoc is to &ldquo;Free Your Mind&rdquo;.  You can not have any negative assumptions about
almost anything.  Again, please trust me.  Amazon Asian Woman!  Might be useful.  Effervescent Ebony Girls!  Might be useful.
Both are amazingly hot, and likely the sources for Apoc Gen2.  If you can&rsquo;t see that, please get your glasses, your cojones,
or whatever does the looking for your body, cleaned and lubed.  Today I hugged #1 and #2 and the ethnicity of neither
affected the hardness of my whatever.</p>

<p>Do the sames girls, but it is hard for me to understand what your hotness sees in a balding wizard like me.  Guest lectures
are quite welcome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site Launch!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/site-launch/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-25T18:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/site-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been working on building up various skills, but wasn&rsquo;t really quite sure &lsquo;why?&rsquo;.  They started forming a pattern
though, and just a few days ago I came up with the title: &ldquo;Zombie Apocalypse Training (or ZAT)&rdquo; and formally used
that when I invited someone to join me for handgun training.</p>

<p>I changed that to &lsquo;ZAP&rsquo; (Preparation) because that is more fun, but ultimately I had to get a URL.  Somehow I realized
&lsquo;training&rsquo; by itself didn&rsquo;t make much sense: I am training to cause the Apoc?  No, I want my community to survive after
the Apoc, so now I was up to &lsquo;ZAST&rsquo;.  That URL was for sale, but I didn&rsquo;t know the price and it was likely a few hundred dollars.</p>

<p>One more shift and voila: EverZast&hellip; ZAST to last forever after the Apoc.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
