<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Zombie Apocolypse Survival Training (ZAST or EverZast)]]></title>
  <link href="http://everzast.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://everzast.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-11-25T22:46:39-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://everzast.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark Fussell]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Free Your Mind!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/free-your-mind/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-25T20:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/free-your-mind</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The number one skill you must have after the Apoc is to &ldquo;Free Your Mind&rdquo;.  You can not have any negative assumptions about
almost anything.  Again, please trust me.  Amazon Asian Woman!  Might be useful.  Effervescent Ebony Girls!  Might be useful.
Both are amazing hot, and likely the sources for Apoc Gen2.  If you can&rsquo;t see that, please get your glasses, your cojones,
or whatever does the looking for your body, cleaned and lubed.  Today I hugged #1 and #2 and the ethnicity of neither
affected the hardness of my whatever.</p>

<p>Do the sames girls, but it is hard for me to understand what your hotness sees in a balding wizard like me.  Guest lectures
are quite welcome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Site Launch!]]></title>
    <link href="http://everzast.com/blog/site-launch/"/>
    <updated>2014-11-25T18:15:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://everzast.com/blog/site-launch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been working on building up various skills, but wasn&rsquo;t really quite sure &lsquo;why?&rsquo;.  They started forming a pattern
though, and just a few days ago I came up with the title: &ldquo;Zombie Apocalypse Training (or ZAT)&rdquo; and formally used
that when I invited someone to join me for handgun training.</p>

<p>I changed that to &lsquo;ZAP&rsquo; (Preparation) because that is more fun, but ultimately I had to get a URL.  Somehow I realized
&lsquo;training&rsquo; by itself didn&rsquo;t make much sense: I am training to cause the Apoc?  No, I want my community to survive after
the Apoc, so now I was up to &lsquo;ZAST&rsquo;.  That URL was for sale, but I didn&rsquo;t know the price and it was likely a few hundred dollars.</p>

<p>One more shift and voila: EverZast&hellip; ZAST to last forever after the Apoc.</p>

<p>Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
